
GOAL?:
    the goal of portfolio optimisation is to find the "efficient frontier" of a given set of assets. The efficient frontier is the set of optimal portfolios that offer the best expected return for a given level of risk.
    Whith this we can understand how best to allocate our fund so that to best combine our assets. This can be used in many strategies that I will attempt to cover in the project. The primary focus of this research will
    focus on the mean-variance model, although I may attempt other models aswell.

What is Mean-Variance?:
    Mean-Variance is a measure of how for a set of numbers is spread out from their mean. In this case we are treating this as Risk.

    How do we use this?:

        Using the following notation:
        -N, the number of assets in our universe
        -μi, the expected return of asset i over a set time period
        -σij, the covariance between returns of asset i and asset j
        -R, the desired expected return of the portfolio chosen

        and decision variables:
        -wi, the proportion of the total inverstment associated with asset i (Note 0<=wi<=1)

        This creates the minimising problem:
        ∑[i=1,N](∑[j=1,N](wi*wj*σij))
        With the constraints that:
        -∑[i=1,N](wi*μi)=R
        -∑[i=1,N](wi)=1
        -0<=wi<=1, i=1,...,N

        this insures that we minimise the risk associated with the portfolio while maintaining the desired respected return of R

    Approach:
    for a given time T, we look into the immediate past for the relevant data. we use this data to produce the values of μi and σij, that are used in our model. This uses in-sample data to attempt co costruct a portfolio
    that should behave the same when out of sample. In practice out-of-sample behaviour will not always be what we observe in-sample.

    The problem is a quadratic optimisation problem, we can solve it easily in python usinf scipy, defining the constraints we outlined earlier and then running the algorithm over many desired returns obtaining our 
    efficient frontier. the python program written here, generates an optimal portfolio curve. I say this because it isnt exactly the efficient frontier as it contains portfolios that have sub-optimal return for a 
    given level of risk (some of the "inefficient frontier"). TO fix this, we find the Global Minimum Variance Portfolio i.e. the critical point of the curve.

    Draw-backs:
    This model is very simple, it doesnt take into account many constraints and features that we would generally see in the real world, these include: transaction costs, restricting proportional asset sizing
    ,restriucting proportional inverstment in different asset sets, rebalancing the portfolio, incorporating both long and short positions.

    Transaction costs:
    The added factor of transaction costs is important, it limits how often we can rebalance our portfolio as to not incur more loss due to fees than potential return. As such, we generally want to include the notion
    of holding periods for which we want to hold the new portfolio. For models taking into account transaction costs, we must consider the amount of time that each portfolio is held, as this cnn effect overall
    returns, although do note that it is quite difficult to accurately adjust holding periods so that to maximise return.
